Muhammad Hashim

Electrical Engineer

1 01008424732	Mit Ghamr - Dakahliyya - Egypt	@ m.hashim.666666@gmail.com
01559544732 № 01008424732 ② 01008424732		

Objectives

Electrical Engineer specialized in Electrical installation, maintenance and troubleshooting of various elevator systems, with 3 years of overall experience in all of them, as well as designing/panel building of elevator control systems, seak to using my technical skills in this field as well as endless improvement of it, by joining a friendly and a growth tolerent work environment.

Education

Mansoura University

Faculty: Faculty of Engineering.
Department: Electrical power and machines.
Grade: 71.35%.

Kum Al-Nur Secondary school (for boys)

Grade: 94.63%.

Work experience

Egypt Gulf for Elevators and Escalators (EGGEEC) [1/9/2021 - Currently]

Headquarter: Sheraton - Madinat Nasr.

Positions:

1/12/2023 - Currently

Position: Maintenance Engineer.

23/9/2022 - 1/12/2023

Position: Elevator Electrical Engineer.

Location: EGGEEC Factory.

21/2/2022 - 23/9/2022

Position: Technical Support Engineer. **Location:** New Adminstrational capital (R6).

1/9/2021 - 20/2/2022

Position: Electric installation Engineer.

Location: New Adminstrational capital (R2 & R6).

Ash-Sherif for melamin [20/1/2021 - 30/7/2021]

Headquarter: Khanka City. **Position:** Maintenance Engineer.

Courses & Achievements

Automation (PLC advanced) $\qquad \qquad \left[6/5/2022 - \text{couldn't finish} \right]$

[21/5/2021 - 15/8/2021]

Training Center: HA Consulting Center.

Location: Al-Abbasiyya/Cairo.

Tracks: PLC Advanced - Industerial Communication - SCADA/HMI

Automation (Classic control + PLC Basic Diploma)

Training Center: HA Consulting Center.

Location: Al-Abbasiyya/Cairo.

Tracks: Classic Control - PLC (basic) - Sensor - VVVF Motor Drives

Skills

Languages				
	Arabic (Nat	tive)		
	English	90		

Technica	al skills
	or Troubleshooting
	Including different local elevator control systems as well as Fuji brand
	Only including Siemens S7-1200 series and S7-300 $+$ Delta's DVP series $+$ Vigor
Motor	Drives $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bigcirc$
	Including Wiring and programming motor drives for well-known brands like Yaskawa, Schneider, Delta, LS, etc.
Contro	ol Panel designing/assembly
	Experienced with elevators' control panels
	<u> </u>
Software	es ·
	+ • • • • • • •
	Especially in embedded system applications
	n
	.AB
	ortal
''	TIA portal is used for programming Siemens' S7-300 and S7-1200 PLCs, as well as uploading code and even
	debugging/monitoring
\ \\ \\ \\ \\ \\ \\ \\ \\ \\ \\ \\ \\ \	
	Point
	pe
	Inscape is a free and a general purpose vector drawing software (an alternative to CoralDraw and Adobe Illustrator).
	For me, it is used for drawing schematic diagrams.
I	
Misc	
Embe	dded systems
	Only 8-bit microcontrollers like PIC16/18 series and AVRs by assembly language and $C/C++$, as well as Arduino
	dev boards
Flectro	

Personal Info

Full Name: Muhammad AbdelMottalib Ibrahim AbdelMottalib Hashin

Date of Birth: 22-8-1994 Nationality: Egyptian Marital status: Single

Millitary service: Temporary Excempted